# Douglas Chan

DATA SCIENTIST

doc225@mail.harvard.edu douglastschanto@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/douglastschan github.com/DouglasChan

647-550-3355

I have worked in various roles: product sourcer, lab manager, and pro-bono data counsel. The fields and knowledge domains were eclectic spanning from brain-computer interfaces, pedagogical MakerSpaces, and settlement sector storytelling. Nevertheless there is a common theme that runs through all these: I have had to be as granular, analytic, and creative as needed to rigorously and demonstratively effect change. It is with this spirit of curiosity and persistence that I will address your challenges, and contribute as a member of your team to its needed solutions.

#### EXPERIENCE

## Lab Manager / Research Coordinator | Virginia Tech CRI

2017-2019, Roanoke, VA

- Recruited, and administered over a dozen neuroscience research protocols with varied research populations including recovering addicts, concussed patients, and hemiparesis children.
- Developed study documents and liaised with research and hospital ethics boards for management of 20 behavioral, animal, and neuroscientific experiments across 3 labs.
- Led frontline team with clinical coordinator during critical planning, testing, and prototyping phase of multi-site, high-impact study with biomedical industry partner.

### Product Sourcer | CubbyCase @ Harvard Innovation Lab

2016-2017 Boston, MA

- Researched products within the educational toy market, home STEM kits, and STEAM products that held high educational potential for an educational subscription box service (https://www.facebook.com/cubbycase).
- Negotiated with company producers on discounts and donations on over a dozen educational products.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BrainStation | Diploma, Data Science**

APR - JUN 2020, Toronto, ON

Harvard Graduate School of Education | Master's of Mind, Brain, & Education (Educational Neuroscience) | S.T.Lee Innovation Grant Recipient (2017)

2016 - 2017, Boston, MA

# McMaster University | Bachelor's of Honors Integrated Sciences, Concentrating in Psychology, Neuroscience & Behavior

2012 - 2016, Hamilton, ON

#### SKILLS

Languages / Platforms : Python, SQL, Java, Matlab, R, UNIX, REDCAP

Visualization: Tableau, Matplotlib, Pyplot

Functional connectivity analysis (conn), Gephi (Network visualization)

Hardware training: MRI operator training on Siemens Trio and Prisma 3 Tesla scanners, Focus Ultrasound ablation system, EEG, fNIRS

Python specializations: NLTK, OpenCV, Gensim, Tweepy, Networkx, Numpy,

Scikitlearn, Pandas, TensorFlow

Psychology: The NIH Toolbox Cognition Battery

#### **PROJECTS**

<u>Twitter Network Explorer</u>: Capstone of an automatic network explorer for Twitter using unsupervised ML, graph theory, and NLP